collegeprowler.com 2019-11-23

# Privacy Policy – Niche

Niche.com, Inc. (“Niche”, “we”, “us”, or “ours”) is committed to protecting your privacy. We have prepared this Privacy Policy (or “Policy”) to describe our practices regarding our collection and use of the personal information of individuals who interact with our mobile apps or website (collectively referred to as our “Site”). This Policy provides information about the types of information that we collect, and what we may do with that information. It also describes with whom we share it, and how we keep it secure.

In this Policy, we will outline and describe the following with respect to the personal information that we collect:

  * Information we collect and its sources
  * How we use your information
  * With whom we share your information
  * Your choices and opting out
  * Cross-border transfers of information
  * How long we keep your information, your right to delete it and correct it
  * Security of your information
  * Liability limits
  * Questions and contact information
  * Children
  * Other important privacy rights

The services that we provide and to which this Policy applies include online services such as email newsletters, online content including relevant targeted ads, scholarship listings, and mobile applications for various medium or devices in use now or in the future (together, the “Services”). 

**I. I** **nformation we collect and its sources**

**_A. Information you provide_** **:**

If you create a login account on our Site, the personal information that you provide includes your name and email address, and such other information as we may require. Also, if you contact us, we collect additional information such as your location, and any personal information that you provide in your contact request. We also collect your personal data when you call us on our service number. This includes information, such as your name and contact information, your phone number as well as the content of your message.

We also collect other information in the form of the content that you choose to submit during your use of our Site. For example, if you apply for or win a scholarship contest, you may be asked for information, such as high school graduation year, that Niche may share with schools for which you have expressed interest. Other information that you may choose to submit when using the Services or our Site includes your age, citizenship, details of academic and work history, work place, preferences and goals related to the Niche Services, test scores and other personally sensitive information entered into your user account. Likewise, if you post in a user review or opinion survey, or comment on one of our articles our blogs, the information that you post becomes public, and is a part of the information about you that we collect. This information may include your personal comments and positions on topics which could include political information and other information of a sensitive nature that you choose to submit.

**_B. Information collected automatically_** **:  **

Whether or not you create an account with us, certain information that identifies you may be passively collected and stored on our or our service providers’ server logs, including your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, operating system and information regarding what pages you accessed when you visited our Site, and when (e.g., the date and time of your visit to our Site), and the information for which you searched and which you viewed. 

We also use “Cookies”, “pixel tags” and other tracking technologies to make our online services more useful to you and to tailor the experience with us to meet your special interests and needs. For information about Cookies, pixel tags and other tracking technologies used on our Site, please see our separate [Cookie Policy ](https://www.niche.com/about/cookie-policy). If you choose to disable Cookies, some aspects of our Services may perform differently, for instance, you will need to re-enter your information each time you return to use the Services.

**_C. Information collected from third parties_** **:  **

We may also collect information about you from any social network or other platform (such as from Facebook, Twitter or other third party social network sites) that you may have connected to or from. This information includes your login and profile information, and the actual social media networks you used. Further, we may associate this personal information obtained from these sources with the other personal information we have collected about you from other sources as described in this Policy. We do not control or supervise how these third party sources process your personal information, and any request that you have regarding the disclosure of your personal information from them to us should be made directly to those third parties (such as Facebook).

In addition to the information that we collect as described above, we also collect information about you from our third party integrators and vendors, such as Google Analytics, Fullstory, surveygizmo, and similar services. Personal data that we collect through these channels includes for example, IP address, access times, browser type and language, device type, device identifiers and Wi-Fi information.

**II. How we use your information**

We use your personal information in order to provide you with meaningful and relevant Services, which includes information about schools, where to live and where to work. To do this, we share some or all of your personal information with authorized representatives of schools, work places, and other entities you designate whose services relate to the Niche Services (“Representatives”). You may “opt out” of any future sharing of your Niche account information from our database at any time in accordance with the process described in Section IV below; however, a Representative may have saved a copy of your account and account-related information from before you opted out.

In addition, we process your personal information for the following purposes:

  * to respond to any questions or comments that you submitted to us on our Site or otherwise;
  * to carry out any obligations entered into between us, such as providing you with Services that you have requested;
  * to notify you of changes to our Services;
  * to seek your views or comments on the Services we provide and send you communications by post, e-mail or text message which you have requested or that may be of interest to you, including newsletters, or promotions of our Services or events;
  * to measure the adequate performance of our interactions with you;
  * to obtain or maintain insurance coverage, manage risks or obtain professional advice and defend our rights and establish, exercise and defend our legal claims; 
  * to facilitate your use of your web account on the Site; or
  * to otherwise provide, create and maintain a trusted online environment and comply with our legal obligations.

**III.** **With whom we share your information**

**_A. Per your instruction or use of the Services/Consents:_**

We may share all categories of your personal information to selected outside companies, either by selling it or otherwise transferring it, to advertisers and other business partners that assist us in providing you with meaningful and relevant Services (each, collectively an “Advertiser”). Our Advertisers include realtors, loan providers and other complementary service companies, schools, work places, and social media platforms such as Facebook. The sharing of your personal information with these Advertisers is conducted in accordance with the contact preferences that you set when you create your user profile, or when you express an interest in any content displayed on our Site, or when you enter a response to any affirmative authorization that you provide by typing it in a space provided or clicking on an icon designed to show your interest in an item on the web page or in the app.  In certain cases, we may ask on behalf of an Advertiser that you have expressed an interest in for your express written consent to receive marketing autodialed or pre-recorded calls or text messages at a phone number you designate. Your consent to such requests is not required as a condition for use of the Niche Services and you can opt out from such calls or texts at any time by following the instructions in such calls or text messages, or by contacting the particular Advertiser directly. Standard message and data rates may apply to calls or texts based on your plan.

In addition, any personal information you share publicly through our Site may be indexed through third party search engines, such as Google or Bing. We do not control the practices of third party search engines, and they may use caches containing your information, including any outdated information. You acknowledge that personal information that you submit when you participate in an opinion survey or user review, a blog or any online message board that we provide through our Site or Services may be available, via the Internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the use (or misuse) of such personal information by others, nor can we ensure it is deleted if you later ask us to delete your personal information as provided for in this Policy. 

**_B. Third party processors:_**

We use third party processors (including contractors and service providers) to provide our web and app services and to help with our operations on our behalf (“Processors”). These Processors need access to and use of your personal information, and include third parties to provide us with technical support, to give us additional personal data about you, and to perform analytics and other work that we may need to outsource. These Processors are bound by law and/or contract to protect the confidentiality and security of your personal information.  They only process your personal information to provide requested services for us, and only act on our documented instructions. In addition, we use certain third party Processors, such as Google’s reCAPTCHA service, to validate login credentials of individuals and to frustrate bots; in these cases, your privacy rights are determined by the Processor’s privacy policy.

We also share all categories of your personal information with other business partners that perform certain functions for us (“Business Partners”).  These Business Partners are themselves responsible to determine the purposes and/or means of the processing your personal information and for the lawfulness of that processing.  They include insurance companies, financial institutions, and other professional advisors.

**_C. Third party websites_** **:**

We provide links to other websites, such as social networking sites (e.g., Facebook, Twitter and Google), or our third party partner websites (such as scholarship providers, schools, and Business Partners), and these other websites may provide links to our Site. Third party sites operate according to their own terms of use and privacy policies and Niche has no control over these third party websites. ** _If you wish to opt-out of any information sharing conducted by any third party website that you link to from us, or to us from them, you must do so in accordance with their specific opt-out policies and procedures._** **_By using our Site and Services, you acknowledge and agree that we are not responsible for the availability of such third-party sites, and do not endorse and are not responsible or liable for any content, advertising, products or other materials on or available from such sites. You further acknowledge and agree that Niche will not be responsible or liable, directly or indirectly, for any damage or loss caused or alleged to be caused by or in connection with use of or reliance on any content, advertising, products, or other materials on or available from such sites.  _**

**_D. De-identified information about you_** **:**

We also share aggregated or de-identified information (i.e., information that does not personally identify you directly), or statistical information about you, including statistical data and historical use data, with others for a variety of purposes, including for their own uses, for example, for improving their services for you and others. 

**_E. As required by law or legitimate business interest_** **:  **

In addition, we may disclose any or all categories of your personal information where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. Likewise, we may disclose all such categories of your personal information to our professional advisers as is reasonably necessary for the purposes of managing risks, obtaining professional advice, or the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. Further, we may share some or all of your personal information in connection with or during negotiation of any merger or similar transaction involving sale or transfer of some or all of our business or assets. If another company acquires our company or assets, that company will possess the personal information collected by us and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.

**IV. Your choices and opting out**

You have the right to request that we do not sell your personal information to Advertisers. If, at some point after giving us your personally identifiable information, you wish to limit the sale of your information to our third party Advertisers, or you no longer desire to continue to receive additional information from us about Niche and our Advertisers, you may have the ability to “opt out” by emailing support@niche.com and putting the words “remove my name” in the subject line of your email. In the case of our email newsletters, you may opt out by clicking on the “opt out” link at the end of each email. If you agree to receive autodialed or pre-recorded calls and/or text messages from an Advertiser and later wish to opt-out, you should follow the direction in such call(s) or text message(s) or contact the school or other Advertiser directly.

Please note, you cannot opt out of our sharing of your personal information with our Processors or Business Partners, or our sharing of deidentified information, or your personal information as required by law or legitimate business interests, as described in Sections III. B., D., and E. above. With respect to information captured and shared through cookies, pixels tags and other tracking technologies, and your ability to limit the sharing of your information through those channels, please refer to our [Cookie Policy](https://www.niche.com/about/cookie-policy) for your options. Also, if you opt out of receiving marketing-related emails from us, we may still send you important administrative messages, from which you cannot opt out.

**_A special note about your telephone number_** – By providing your telephone number to us, you agree that this action constitutes an “inquiry” for purposes of telemarketing laws. Regardless of the fact that your telephone and/or mobile number may be listed with the Federal Do-Not-Call Registry or your State Do-Not-Call list, **_you are providing your express written consent to receive future information (including telemarketing) about products and services from us, and you hereby agree and consent to our contacting you using the information you have provided and will provide to us. This means we may contact you by e-mail, phone and/or mobile number (including use of automated dialing equipment and/or pre-recorded calls), text (SMS) message, social networks or any other means of communication that your wireless or other telecommunications device may be capable of receiving (e.g., video, etc.). You are not required to agree to this consent in order to obtain Services through us. This consent may be revoked by you at any time and by any reasonable means, including by emailing us at support@niche.com and putting the words “remove my telephone number” in the subject line of your email, or by telephoning us at 1-(844)-452-7758_** ** _._** Please refer to the [Niche User Agreement](https://www.niche.com/about/terms/) for additional information regarding telephone consent.

**_Special rule for users under 16 years of age_** – So long as we have actual knowledge that you are under the age of 16, we will not sell your personally identifiable information to our Advertisers unless you “opt in” by requesting us to do so. You can opt in to information sharing with Advertisers by requesting that we share your information with schools for which you have expressed an interest or with parties that you wish to be considered for a scholarship. Likewise, any public information that you post on the Site, including user reviews or opinion surveys, are considered public and you will be considered to have opted in to the sharing of such public information.  You may also request that we share your personally identifiable information with our Advertisers by contacting us at support@niche.com, and telling us that you wish to opt in. 

**V. Cross-border transfers of information** ****

Our Site and the Services we offer through it are U.S. based and are controlled, operated and administered by Niche and its Processors from offices and servers within the United States. Our Site and this Privacy Policy is strictly intended for audiences located in the United States and are provided in accordance with and subject to applicable United States law. If you decide to continue to access our Site from your location outside the United States, you hereby agree that your use of the Site or any Services we may offer are subject to this Policy and your personal information will be transferred or processed in the United States, and you may have fewer privacy rights and protections than you have in your country of origin.

**VI. How long we keep your personal information, your right to delete and correct it  **

We retain your personal information as reasonably necessary to fulfill the purposes for which we collected it and you provided it, and to comply with our legal obligations. In no event will we keep your personal information for longer than is reasonably necessary for the purposes defined in this Policy. You also have the right to request that we delete your personal information, subject to certain exceptions, such as our need to prevent and protect against fraud or other illegal activity, to complete business transactions with you, and for such other purposes as allowed by law. You can correct or update your personal information by updating your profile or by contacting us. For more information on where and how long your personal information is stored, your requests to delete it or correct it, please contact us at the address set forth below in Section IX.

**VII.** **Security of your information** ** **

To help protect the privacy of your Personal Data collected by us, we maintain reasonable physical, technical and administrative safeguards. We update and test our security technology on an ongoing basis. We restrict access to your personal information to those employees who need to know that information in order to provide Services to you. In addition, we train our employees about the importance of confidentiality and maintaining the privacy and security of your information.

**VIII.** **Limitation of liability**

YOU UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT ANY DISPUTE OVER THE PRIVACY OF YOUR INFORMATION IS SUBJECT TO THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND THE NICHE USER AGREEMENT (INCLUDING ANY INDEMNIFICATION AND LIMITATIONS ON DAMAGES CONTAINED IN THAT AGREEMENT).

**IX. Questions, concerns or complaints – Contact Details**

If you have questions about our privacy practices and this Privacy Policy, or if you wish to correct any of your information or exercise your rights under the law or this Policy, you can contact us as follows: 

Niche.com, Inc.

2840 Liberty Avenue

Suite 202

Pittsburgh, PA. 15222

Email: support@niche.com

Toll Free – (844)-452-7758

Please be specific when telling us what your request is.

**X. A note about Children**

Children under the age of 13 are not permitted to use the Niche Site or Services and we do not intentionally collect or maintain personal information from those who are under 13 years old. Protecting the privacy of children is very important to us. Thus, if we obtain actual knowledge that a user is under 13, we will take steps to remove that user’s personal information from our databases. We recommend that children between the ages of 13 and 18 obtain their parent’s permission before submitting information over the Internet. By using the Niche Site or Services, you are representing that you are at least 18 years old, or that you are at least 13 years old and have your parents’ permission to use the website and any Services offered by us.

**XI. NOTICE TO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS – YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

**(AS PROVIDED BY CALIFORNIA CIVIL CODE SECTION 1798.83)**

**A CALIFORNIA RESIDENT WHO HAS PROVIDED PERSONAL DATA TO A BUSINESS WITH WHOM HE/SHE HAS ESTABLISHED A BUSINESS RELATIONSHIP FOR PERSONAL, FAMILY, OR HOUSEHOLD PURPOSES (A “CALIFORNIA CUSTOMER”) MAY REQUEST INFORMATION ABOUT WHETHER THE BUSINESS HAS DISCLOSED PERSONAL INFORMATION TO ANY THIRD PARTIES FOR THE THIRD PARTIES’ DIRECT MARKETING PURPOSES. IN GENERAL, IF THE BUSINESS HAS MADE SUCH A DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL DATA, UPON RECEIPT OF A REQUEST BY A CALIFORNIA CUSTOMER, THE BUSINESS IS REQUIRED TO PROVIDE A LIST OF ALL THIRD PARTIES TO WHOM PERSONAL DATA WAS DISCLOSED IN THE PRECEDING CALENDAR YEAR, AS WELL AS A LIST OF THE CATEGORIES OF PERSONAL DATA THAT WERE DISCLOSED. CALIFORNIA CUSTOMERS MAY REQUEST FURTHER INFORMATION ABOUT OUR COMPLIANCE WITH THIS LAW BY CONTACTING US BY EMAIL AT** **_support@niche.com_** **, OR BY WRITING TO US AT** ** _2840 Liberty_** ** _Avenue, Suite 202, Pittsburgh, PA. 15222 C/O “CA PRIVACY”_** **, or by calling us at the toll free number** **(844)-452-7758.** **PLEASE NOTE THAT WE ARE REQUIRED TO RESPOND TO UP TO TWO REQUESTS PER CALIFORNIA CUSTOMER EACH YEAR AND WE ARE NOT REQUIRED TO RESPOND TO REQUESTS MADE BY MEANS OTHER THAN THROUGH THIS E-MAIL OR STREET ADDRESS OR TOLL-FREE TELEPHONE NUMBER.**

Except as provided in Section III, above, we do not share your personal information collected by us with third parties for their direct marketing purposes without giving you the opportunity to opt out as more fully described above in Section IV. If you are a California resident, you may request information about our compliance with California law by calling us toll free at (844)-452-7758, emailing us, or by sending a letter to us at the number and/or address shown above in Section IX, addressed to “Attention: California Privacy Matters.”  Any such request must include “California Privacy Rights Request” in the subject line and include your name, street address, city, state and ZIP code. Please note that we are only required to respond to up to two requests per visitor each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this designated email address, mailing address or toll-free number.

California Business & Professions Code Section 22575(b) provides that California residents are entitled to know how Niche responds to “Do Not Track” browser settings. We currently do not respond to “Do Not Track” signals because a uniform technological standard has not yet been developed.

**XII.** **Changes to this Privacy Policy and Effective Date**

We may make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time and for any reason, including our business reasons or in order to comply with changing privacy laws. Unless otherwise provided by applicable law, any changes that we make to this Policy will be published on our Site and will become effective upon publication. Your continued use of the Services or the Site will constitute your acceptance of any such changes to the fullest extent permitted by law. You are encouraged to review this Policy from time to time, to make sure you are current with our privacy practices.

**_The Effective Date of this Privacy Policy is: November 13, 2019_**
